McKenzie Peterson

979-450-5312 | Atlanta, GA (open to relocate) | petersonmckenzie67@gmail.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/mckenzie-peterson

Portfolio: https://mhpmhp27167.github.io/McKenzie Peterson.github.io/

History graduate turned UX Designer with a relentless curiosity for human behavior. Strong writer. Background in Visual Arts and Museum Studies. Recently worked alongside a team to design two original mobile applications and two responsive web redesigns. Passionate about responsive-web redesigns and iterating designs based on insights from user research.

Technical Skills

<u>UX/UI:</u> Adobe Creative Cloud, Adobe XD, Sketch, Figma, Invision, Zeplin, Miro,

<u>Research</u>: Survey Writing, Social Media Analytics (Crimson Hexagon), Usability Testing, A/B Testing, Wireframing & Prototyping

<u>Web Development:</u> HTML5, Javascript, JQuery, CSS, Bootstrap 5, Github, Visual Studio Code, Webflow <u>Soft Skills</u>: Team Collaboration, Leadership, Attention to Detail, Public Speaking, Technical Curiosity

Recent Projects

Atlanta Film Series | October 2020 | https://tinyurl.com/yxp9lnyp

Responsive Web Redesign of an event website integrating 4 unique websites into one accessible product.

Responsible for building out the user interface of the website and conducting five user research interviews.

Skills: Logo Redesign, Responsive Web Design using HTML, CSS, and Javascript

Money Tree | https://tinyurl.com/y4ww64gq

An interactive budgeting tool for Millenials.

Designed a high-fidelity prototype and presented key features to stakeholders.

Skills: IOS, Mobile Applications, Adobe XD

Lifeline Animal Project Pet-matching Mobile Application | https://tinyurl.com/y4jwjgug A pet-dating mobile app that matches adoptable shelter pets with pet owners.

Wrote two user research plans to test key features for usability and heuristic insights. Skills: User Research, User Surveys, Non-profit

Education

Georgia Tech University | Atlanta, GA (Remote) | September 2020 Certificate in User Experience and Interaction Design Program

The University of Georgia, Honors College | Athens, GA | December 2019 Bachelor of Arts in History, Studio Art Minor, Certificate in Museum Studies Magna Cum Laude, Cumulative GPA 3.83/4.0

Work Experience

Customer Service Associate | The UPS Store | Macon, GA | October 2020

- Greets over 200 customers daily with friendly and prompt customer service
- Recognized by the manager for quick learning and useful problem-solving skills during the busy shipping season.
- Analyzed common user experience challenges associated with the customer's experience at The UPS Store. Offered constructive solutions to customers and management.

Communications Intern | The Georgia Museum of Art | Athens, GA | January 2019 - May 2019

- Researched and wrote about artists and works of art in informative weekly blog posts
- Crafted 10 press releases about museum events and exhibitions
- Interviewed curators and other professional about upcoming exhibitions
- Analyzed 2 years of social media data with Crimson Hexagon software and suggested 3 creative solutions to increase social media engagement with the museum audience.

Childcare Provider | YMCA Athens | Athens, GA | January 2020 - March 2020

- Cared for children ages 6 weeks to 12 years old by maintaining a safe play environment and facilitating interactive games and activities.
- Informed children's parents or guardians about daily activities, behaviors, and related concerns about their child's experience at the YMCA.

Lifeguard | Ramsey Aquatics | Athens, GA | August 2018 - November 2019

- Responded to emergencies with appropriate care and professionalism
- Organized data about mile swim club into Microsoft Excel. Emailed participants their total swim mileage each month.

Leadership and Volunteer Experience

Club Cross Country President | Competitive Sports | January 2017- January 2019

- Communicated team goals through public speaking and social media to 70 team members.
- Increased team competition participation by 10% by implementing new email and social media communication campaigns.
- Implemented necessary travel arrangements for each competition. Responsible for allocation of team funds.

8th Grade History Campus Tour Guide | University of Georgia | March 2019